<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division</origin>
				<pubdate>2009</pubdate>
				<title>NHGIS: TIGER/Line Shapefile, 2009, 2000 state, 108th Congressional District</title>
				<edition>2009</edition>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<onlink>www.nhgis.org</onlink>
				<origin>Minnesota Population Center</origin></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>The NHGIS is a National Institutes of Health and National Science Foundation-sponsored project to create a digital spatial-temporal database of all available historical US aggregate census materials. The available shapefiles on the NHGIS site represent version 2.0 of historical US state/territory boundary files for the 1790 to 2010 decennial censuses and American Community Survey releases.
The TIGER/Line Shapefiles are an extract of selected geographic and cartographic information from the Census MAF/TIGER database.  The Census MAF/TIGER database represents a seamless national file with no overlaps or gaps between parts.  However, each TIGER/Line Shapefile is designed to stand alone as an independent data set or the shapefiles can be combined to cover the whole nation.</abstract>
			<purpose>These data are based upon work supported by the National Institutes of Health and the National Science Foundation. Its purpose is twofold. First, the NHGIS created and freely distributes a database incorporating all available aggregate census information for the United States between 1790 and 2010. The database contains information for a wide variety of statistical (blocks, block groups, census tracts, metropolitan statistical areas, etc.) and administrative units (places, minor civil divisions, counties, states, etc.). Second, the NHGIS produced and freely distributes boundary files for small areas (census tracts and counties) in the United States. Boundary files for tracts are available for the 1910-2010 decennial censuses and American Community Survey releases, and boundary files for counties and states/territories are available for the 1790-2010 decennial censuses and American Community Survey releases. The boundaries contained in this file do not necessarily represent current legal boundaries. Instead, they represent the boundaries over which the U.S. Census Bureau tabulated and published data at that time.
In order for others to use the information in the Census MAF/TIGER database in a geographic information system (GIS) or for other geographic applications, the Census Bureau releases to the public extracts of the database in the form of TIGER/Line Shapefiles.</purpose>
			<Subject_Entity>Alabama(01)</Subject_Entity>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<rngdates>
					<begdate>200901</begdate>
					<enddate>200905</enddate>
				</rngdates>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>TIGER/Line Shapefiles are extracted from the Census MAF/TIGER database.  No changes or updates will be made to this version of the TIGER/Line Shapefiles.  Future releases of TIGER/Line Shapefiles will reflect updates made to the Census MAF/TIGER database.</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-88.473227</westbc>
				<eastbc>-84.888246</eastbc>
				<northbc>35.008028</northbc>
				<southbc>30.144425</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
				<themekey>boundaries</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>State or equivalent entity</themekey>
				<themekey>Polygon</themekey>
				<themekey>Congressional Districts</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>INCITS.38-200x (R2004),INCITS.31-200x (R2007),INCITS.454-200x,INCITS 455-200x,INCITS 446-2008</placekt>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
				<placekey>U.S.</placekey>
				<placekey>State or Equivalent Entity</placekey>
				<placekey>Alabama</placekey>
				<placekey>AL</placekey>
				<placekey>01</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>This dataset was produced with an intended application at the state/territory, regional or national level. Appropriate uses include thematic mapping of census data and spatial analysis of census data. These unaltered data may be redistributed by a third party. If these data are altered or incorporated into another dataset, they are not to be redistributed without also: altering the name of the dataset, including a Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata (FGDC-STD-001-1998) compliant metadata file that describes the dataset and reflects the alteration steps that makes the new dataset different from this one, and citing this dataset in the metadata as a source for the altered dataset using the source citation specified below. If these digital data are used in the production of a report or in the compilation of a standalone printed map, then this dataset is to be cited in the report or on the map using the source citation specified below. The following source citation should be used when citing this dataset: Minnesota Population Center. National Historical Geographic Information System: Version 2.0, Minneapolis: MN, University of Minnesota 2011. No fee may be charged for use or distribution. Publications and research reports based on the database must cite it appropriately. Users are requested to send a copy of any publications, research reports, or educational material making use of the data or documentation. Printed matter should be sent to: NHGIS Minnesota Population Center University of Minnesota 50 Willey Hall 225 19th Avenue South Minneapolis, MN 55455.
The TIGER/Line Shapefile products are not copyrighted however TIGER/Line and Census TIGER are registered trademarks of the U.S. Census Bureau.  These products are free to use in a product or publication, however acknowledgement must be given to the U.S. Census Bureau as the source.
The boundary information in the TIGER/Line Shapefiles are for statistical data collection and tabulation purposes only; their depiction and designation for statistical purposes does not constitute a determination of jurisdictional authority or rights of ownership or entitlement and they are not legal land descriptions.Coordinates in the TIGER/Line shapefiles have six implied decimal places, but the positional accuracy of these coordinates is not as great as the six decimal places suggest.</useconst>
		<Title_13_Restrictions>Yes, the data are free from Title 13 restrictions</Title_13_Restrictions>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Minnesota Population Center</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>50 Willey Hall, 225 19th Ave S</address>
					<city>Minneapolis</city>
					<state>MN</state>
					<postal>55455</postal>
					<country>United States</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>612-625-7375</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>nhgis@umn.edu</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
	</idinfo>
	<Data_Set_Character_Set>8859part1</Data_Set_Character_Set>
	<Data_Set_Language>eng</Data_Set_Language>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>Accurate against Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS), FIPS Publication 6-4, and FIPS-55 at the 100% level for the codes and base names.  The remaining attribute information has been examined but has not been fully tested for accuracy.</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>The Census Bureau performed automated tests to ensure logical consistency and limits of shapefiles.  Segments making up the outer and inner boundaries of a polygon tie end-to-end to completely enclose the area.  All polygons are tested for closure.
The Census Bureau uses its internally developed geographic update system to enhance and modify spatial and attribute data in the Census MAF/TIGER database.  Standard geographic codes, such as FIPS codes for states, counties, municipalities, county subdivisions, places, American Indian/Alaska Native/Native Hawaiian areas, and congressional districts are used when encoding spatial entities.  The Census Bureau performed spatial data tests for logical consistency of the codes during the compilation of the original Census MAF/TIGER database files.  Most of the codes for geographic entities except states, counties, urban areas, Core Based Statistical Areas (CBSAs), American Indian Areas (AIAs), and congressional districts were provided to the Census Bureau by the USGS, the agency responsible for maintaining FIPS 55.  Feature attribute information has been examined but has not been fully tested for consistency.
For the TIGER/Line Shapefiles, the Point and Vector Object Count for the G-polygon SDTS Point and Vector Object Type reflects the number of records in the shapefile attribute table.  For multi-polygon features, only one attribute record exists for each multi-polygon rather than one attribute record per individual G-polygon component of the multi-polygon feature.  TIGER/Line Shapefile multi-polygons are an exception to the G-polygon object type classification.  Therefore, when multi-polygons exist in a shapefile, the object count will be less than the actual number of G-polygons.</logic>
		<complete>Data completeness of the TIGER/Line Shapefiles reflects the contents of the Census MAF/TIGER database at the time the TIGER/Line Shapefiles were created.</complete>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Department of Commerce, U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division</origin>
						<pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
						<title>Census MAF/TIGER database</title>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>200901</begdate>
							<enddate>200905</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>MAF/TIGER</srccitea>
				<srccontr>The selected geographic and cartographic information (line segments) are derived from the U.S. Census Bureau's Master Address File Topologically Integrated Geographic Encoding and Referencing (MAF/TIGER) database.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>TIGER/Line Shapefiles are extracted from the Census MAF/TIGER database by nation, state, county, and entity.  Census MAF/TIGER data for the nation, state, county, and entity are then distributed among 58 shapefiles each containing attributes for line, polygon, or landmark geographic data. </procdesc>
				<srcused>Census MAF/TIGER</srcused>
				<procdate>2009</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep><procdesc>Dataset Copied.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Erased coastal water features. Added and calculated GISJOIN.

Unlike all other geographic levels, the original 2009 TIGER Congressional District files came with unique, partially erased coastlines. As a result, the coastlines for Congressional Districts files may not align with the coastline of files of other geographic levels.</procdesc></procstep></lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<indspref>Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS), ANSI, and feature names.</indspref>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf><esriterm Name="US_cd108th_2000_Erased_All"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">0</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983 in the 48 contiguous states, the District of Columbia, Alaska, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and the Pacific Island Areas.</horizdn>
				<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298257</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="US_cd108th_2000_Erased_All">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>CD108.shp</enttypl>
				<enttypd>108th Congressional District</enttypd>
				<enttypds>U.S. Census Bureau</enttypds>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">0</enttypc></enttyp>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>STATEFP00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 state Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<codesetd>
						<codesetn>INCITS.38-200x (R2004), Codes for the Identification of the States, 
the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the United States (Formerly FIPS 5-2)
					</codesetn>
						<codesets>U.S. Census Bureau</codesets>
					</codesetd>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">STATEFP00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>CD108FP</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>108th congressional district Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>00</edomv>
						<edomvd>At Large Representation</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>98</edomv>
						<edomvd>Non-Voting Delegate</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>99</edomv>
						<edomvd>No Representation</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>01 to 53</edomv>
						<edomvd>Congressional District (in states with more than one district)</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">CD108FP</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>CD108IDFP</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>108th congressional district identifier, a concatenation of Census 2000 state Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) code, the 108th congressional session code, and the 108th congressional district FIPS code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<codesetd>
						<codesetn>INCITS.38-200x (R2004), Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the United States (Formerly FIPS 5-2), the congressional session code that appears in CDSESSN, and the 108th congressional district code that appears in CD108FP</codesetn>
						<codesets>U.S. Census Bureau</codesets>
					</codesetd>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">CD108IDFP</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">7</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>NAMELSAD00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 name and the translated legal/statistical area description for congressional district</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Use values from the CD108FP field and the translated legal/statistical area description code for congressional district that appears in LSAD00</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">NAMELSAD00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">41</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>LSAD00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 legal/statistical area description code for congressional district</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>00</edomv>
						<edomvd>Blank</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>C1</edomv>
						<edomvd>Congressional District (at Large)</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>C2</edomv>
						<edomvd>Congressional District (prefix)</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>C3</edomv>
						<edomvd>Resident Commissioner District (at Large)</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>C4</edomv>
						<edomvd>Delegate District (at Large)</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<edom>
						<edomv>C5</edomv>
						<edomvd>No Representative</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">LSAD00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>CDSESSN</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>108th congressional session code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>108</edomv>
						<edomvd>congressional district session code</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">CDSESSN</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">3</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>MTFCC00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>MAF/TIGER feature class code</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>G5200</edomv>
						<edomvd>Congressional District</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">MTFCC00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">5</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FUNCSTAT00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 functional status</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>N</edomv>
						<edomvd>Nonfunctioning legal entity</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">FUNCSTAT00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>ALAND00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 land area</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>0 to 9,999,999,999,999</edomv>
						<edomvd>Blank</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ALAND00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">18</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">8</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>AWATER00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 water area</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>0 to 9,999,999,999,999</edomv>
						<edomvd>Blank</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">AWATER00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">18</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">8</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>INTPTLAT00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 latitude of the internal point</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>00</edomv>
						<edomvd>Blank</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">INTPTLAT00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">11</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">GISJOIN</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">GISJOIN</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">6</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>unique identifier for joining to NHGIS tabular data</attrdef><attrdefs>NHGIS</attrdefs></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>INTPTLON00</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Census 2000 longitude of the internal point</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>00</edomv>
						<edomvd>Blank</edomvd>
						<edomvds>U.S. Census Bureau</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">INTPTLON00</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_AREA</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_AREA</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_LEN</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_LEN</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Minnesota Population Center</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntvoice>612-625-7375</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>nhgis@umn.edu</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<distliab>No warranty, expressed or implied is made with regard to the accuracy of these data, and no liability is assumed by the U.S. Government in general or the U.S. Census Bureau in specific as to the spatial or attribute accuracy of the data.  The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty and no responsibility is assumed by the U.S. government in the use of these files.  The boundary information in the TIGER/Line Shapefiles is for statistical data collection and tabulation purposes only; their depiction and designation for statistical purposes do not constitute a determination of jurisdictional authority or rights of ownership or entitlement and they are not legal land descriptions.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>TGRSHP (compressed)</formname>
					<filedec>PK-ZIP, version 1.93 A or higher</filedec>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
					<offoptn>
						<offmedia>DVD-ROM (Only if offered offline)</offmedia>
						<recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt>
					</offoptn>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>The online copy of the TIGER/Line files may be accessed without charge.</fees>
			<ordering>To obtain more information about ordering TIGER/Line shapefiles visit http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger </ordering>
		</stdorder>
		<techpreq>The TIGER/Line shapefiles contain geographic data only and do not include display mapping software or statistical data.  For information on how to use the TIGER/Line shapefile data with specific software package users shall contact the company that produced the software.</techpreq>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20090507</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Minnesota Population Center</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntvoice>612-625-7375</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>nhgis@umn.edu</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<Metadata_Character_Set>8859part1</Metadata_Character_Set>
		<Metadata_File_Identifier>tl_2009_01_cd108.shp.xml</Metadata_File_Identifier>
		<Metadata_Language>eng</Metadata_Language>
	</metainfo>
	<Esri><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\thalia.socsci.umn.edu\ipums\istads\data\shape\tl2009\base\nongen\US_cd108th_2000_Erased_All.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><itemName Sync="TRUE">US_cd108th_2000_Erased_All</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><itemSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</itemSize></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="C:\Workspace\TIGER2009_unzip\tl_2009_01_cd108" dest="\\MPC-5DBDFQ1\C$\Workspace\TIGER2009_unzip\cd108\tl_2009_01_cd108" date="20140403" time="08460800"></copy></copyHistory><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Meter (1.000000)</csUnits><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.1'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;USA_Contiguous_Albers_Equal_Area_Conic&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Albers&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-96.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_1&amp;quot;,29.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_2&amp;quot;,45.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,37.5],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;ESRI&amp;quot;,102003]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-16901100&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-8579000&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;266467840.99085236&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;102003&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;102003&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml><projcsn Sync="TRUE">USA_Contiguous_Albers_Equal_Area_Conic</projcsn></coordRef><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.2\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CalculateField" Date="20140929" Time="125324">CalculateField NHGIS.US_cd108th_2009_1 GISJOIN ""G" &amp; [STATEFP00] &amp; "0" &amp; [CD108FP]" VB #</Process></lineage></DataProperties><SyncDate>20141013</SyncDate><SyncTime>15054300</SyncTime><ModDate>20141013</ModDate><ModTime>15054300</ModTime><CreaDate>20140929</CreaDate><CreaTime>12483300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.2.0.3348</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">US_cd108th_2000_Erased_All</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></mdLang><distInfo><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distFormat><distTranOps><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distTranOps></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="102003" Sync="TRUE"></identCode><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">ESRI</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">10.2.0</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="US_cd108th_2000_Erased_All"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">0</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20141013</mdDateSt></metadata>
